二零二三年山西省初中学业水平考试。
一情景反应，本题共五个小题，
每小题你将听到一组对话，请你从每小题所给的
B, Of course!
三幅图片。
中，选出与你所听到的信息相关联的一项。
粽子
粽子?
It's the Dragon Boat Festival today!
3. The sofa looks so nice!
Thanks! I got it from a yard sale.
The sofa looks so nice!
4. I'd like to wear a t -shirt to the party.
That's okay. That one is perfect.
I'd like to wear a t -shirt to the party.
5. Where were you yesterday afternoon?
I was having a picnic with my family in the park.
Where were you yesterday afternoon?
I was having a with my family in the park.
二，对话理解。
本题共五个小题，每小题你将听到一组对话和一个问题，
请你从每小题。
你所给的
B, 6. Jim, our school needs volunteers.
三个选项中选出一个最佳选项。
Let's plant trees with Tony.
Okay, I've heard Lucy is going to clean up the park with her group.
Jim, our school needs volunteers.
Let's plant trees with Tony.
7. Excuse me, could you tell me the way to the nearest store?
Sure, just go along the street, pass a cinema and a restaurant, the store is on your
right. Sure, Sure,
go restaurant, right.
8. me, could you tell me the way to the nearest store?
Sure, just go along the street, pass a cinema and a restaurant, and the store is on
your right. Question,
where is the woman going?
8. you seem to be really busy.
Yes, I'm busy setting up an art club for my students.
I hope to make their school life more colorful.
8. you Question, what does John probably do?
Question, 9. It is such a long walk.
I can't move my legs.
Come on, honey.
We will get home soon, and then you can have a rest.
Question, how is the girl feeling now?
It is such a long walk.
I can't move my legs.
Come on, honey.
We will get home soon, and then you can have a rest.
Question, how is the girl feeling now?
10. It takes you a long time to write to school every day.
I don't mind it.
I see it as a kind of exercise.
Question, what does the boy mean?
It takes you a long time to write to school every day.
I don't mind it.
I see it as a kind of exercise.
Question, what does the boy mean?
三，语篇理解。
本题你将听到一篇短文，请你根据短文内容和所提出的五个问题，从每小
题所给的
A, B, I can still remember the day when Mom talked with me.
三个。
选项中选出一个最佳选项。
At that time, I was in grade eight.
I began to become less interested in science.
Although I was very good at science, I gave up a bit with it.
I didn't work so hard as before.
I didn't really see why I had to try.
That afternoon, Mom asked me what I wanted to do when I grew up.
I could answer the question easily.
I love cars, so I told her I wanted to fix cars.
What about making cars?
I mean being an engineer.
Maybe you can make the best cars in the world, said Mom.
That sounds pretty cool.
It is something I've never thought about, I said.
Well, said Mom, you are good at science, but you are not really trying.
I just find it's a bit boring, I said.
It is sometimes boring, said Mom, but studying is like climbing a mountain.
As long as you stick to your goal and keep moving, you can get to the top.
Only when you get to the top can you see something really beautiful.
Mom was right.
I came to know my dream.
When I was in grade nine, I was really enjoying science, and I am now an engineer.
I really feel like I'm on top of that mountain at last.
I can still remember the day when Mom talked with me.
At that time, I was in grade eight.
I began to become less interested in science.
Although I was very good at science, I gave up a bit with it.
I didn't work so hard as before.
I didn't really see why I had to try.
That afternoon, asked me what I wanted to do when I grew up.
I could answer the question easily.
love cars, so I told her I wanted to fix cars.
What about making cars?
I mean being an engineer.
Maybe you can make the best cars in the world, said Mom.
That sounds pretty cool.
It is something I've never thought about, I said.
Well, said Mom, you are good at science, but you are not really trying.
I just find it's a bit boring, I said.
It is sometimes boring, said Mom, but studying is like climbing a mountain.
As long as you stick to your goal and keep moving, you can get to the top.
Only when you get to the top can you see something really beautiful.
Mom was right.
I came to know my dream.
When I was in grade nine, I was really enjoying science, and I am now an engineer.
I really feel like I'm on top of that mountain at last.
四，听力填空。
本题你将听到一篇短文，请你根据所听内容完成下面的句子，每空一词。
following sentence according to lecture.
Hi, everyone. today's class meeting, I'd like to introduce the labor star of our
school, Li You know, he is 15 years old and likes cooking very much.
Li Lei started cooking at a very young age.
When he was 10, he made a cake for his mom.
It was terrible.
It was the first time he had helped his mom in the kitchen.
He was 11 when he made his first meal, tomato and egg noodles.
Gradually, he fell in love with cooking.
To make a good meal, he had to practice again and again.
Now he has his own cooking shows on the Internet.
They are watched by thousands of people.
He really enjoys himself making the shows.
His mom and dad usually enjoy his food, and they are glad that they don't have to
make dinner every weekend.
Actually, Li is really happy that he can help around the house through his hobby.
You see, Li Lei sets a good example for us.
Let's follow him.
Hi, everyone! today's class meeting, I'd like to introduce the labor star of our
school, Li You know, he is 15 years old and likes cooking very much.
Li Lei started cooking at a very young age.
When he was 10, he made a cake for his mom.
It was terrible.
It was the first time he had helped his mom in the kitchen.
He was 11 when he made his first meal, tomato and egg noodles.
Gradually, he fell in love with cooking.
To make a good meal, he had to practice again and again.
Now he has his own cooking shows on the Internet.
They are watched by thousands of people.
He really enjoys himself making the shows.
His mom and dad usually enjoy his food, and they are glad that they don't have to
make dinner every weekend.
Actually, Li is really happy that he can help around the house through his hobby.
You see, Li Lei sets a good example for us.
Let's follow him.
You Li You see, example You
You see,